Finding Aid for Olivia Maynard papers, 1976-1982
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
Olivia Maynard papers 1976-1982
Maynard, Olivia.
1 linear foot
2009075 Aa 2
Michigan State Democratic Party officer, candidate for public office; regent of the University of Michigan; topical files, speeches, and miscellaneous.
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
The collection came from the offices of the Democratic Party of Michigan (donor no. 4474 ) and from Olivia Maynard (donor no. 9846 ).
No further additions to the papers are expected.
The collection is open to research.
Olivia Procter Maynard was born on June 24, 1936 in Cincinnati, Ohio. She later moved to Flint, Michigan. She received a Bachelor's degree in political science from George Washington University 1958 and a Master's Degree in social work from the University of Michigan in 1971.
Active in the state Democratic Party beginning in 1964, Maynard has served as recording secretary 1967-1971; vice chair 1971-1979; and from 1979 to 1983 as party chair, the first woman to hold this office. In 1983, Governor Blanchard named her to head the Office of Services to the Aging. She ran unsuccessfully for Lieutenant Governor in 1978 and 1990.
Maynard next worked as an adjunct professor and instructor of aging policy at the University of Michigan, Michigan State University, and the Lansing Community College Center for Aging Education. She was also the founder and president of Michigan Prospect, a progressive public policy institute, and she served on the Federal Council on Aging during the Clinton administration. She has been a Regent at the University of Michigan since 1996.
The Olivia Maynard papers document the period of 1977 to 1982, when she was engaged in state Democratic politics and in organizations relating to women's rights. Some of the files concern her campaign for lieutenant governor in 1978. In addition, the collection includes several folders of her speeches given both as a candidate and as a party official.
Subjects:
Democratic Party (Mich.); Elections--Michigan--1978.; Maynard, Olivia.; Michigan--Politics and government--1951-; Michigan--Politics and government--1971-1980.; Michigan--Politics and government--1981-1990.; Women in politics--Michigan.; Women's rights--United States.
- Olivia Maynard (Personal)
  - Biographical (Box 1)
  - Speeches
    - Undated (Box 1)
    - 1977 (Box 1)
    - 1978, 2 folders (Box 1)
    - 1979 (Box 1)
    - 1980 (Box 1)
    - 1981 (Box 1)
    - 1982 (Box 1)
  - Campaigns and Elections, 1978
    - Fitzgerald/Maynard, 2 folders (Box 1)
    - Milliken/Bradley (includes clippings and reports) (Box 1)
    - Tax Limitation (clippings, articles, reports) (Box 1)
  - Women's issues, 1976-1979
    - Abortion (Michigan related) (mostly clippings and articles) (Box 1)
    - Divorce (Jean L. King, "Divorce in Michigan," 1976 and clipping) (Box 1)
    - Discrimination in Education (clippings, statistics) (Box 1)
    - Legal Rights (brochures, excerpts) (Box 1)
    - Michigan Women's Commission (clippings, reports, correspondence) (Box 1)
    - National Conference of Women, 4 folders (Box 1)
    - Organizations: State and National (brochures, bulletins, correspondence) (Box 1)
    - Workforce (mostly UAW material) (Box 1)
  - Documents regarding 1982 reapportionment process (Box 1)
  - Miscellaneous (Box 1)
Related Material
The records of the state Democratic Party contain files of Olivia Maynard from the various positions she held within the party organization.